### Afshin Tavakkoli

(UI/UX Designer)

Location: Lisbon Metropolitan Area, Portugal

Phone number: +351 915 725 639 Email: afshin344@gmail.com

Linked In: www.linkedin.com/in/afshin344/

Portfolio: https://www.afshix.com/

### Summary

A UI/UX designer with over 6 years of experience in a variety of digital platforms including responsive webpages, native apps, and PWA. Expert at collaborating with startup teams in the implementation of UI/UX design strategies in several industries to deliver exceptional user experiences, through streamlined processes and optimized workflows.

#### Skills and technical Proficiencies

#### 1. User experience

- User-centric Design
- Mobile App Design
- Responsive web design
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Usability testing
- User Research
- Accessibility
- Gamification
- Scrum Framework

#### 2. User interface

- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Balsamiq Wireframes
- Zeplin
- Marvel
- Familiar with (Html, CSS, Bootstrap)
- Logo Design (Typography)

### Professional Experience

## 1. Motoproz, United Kingdom UI / UX Designer

09/2023 - 02/2024

A web-based platform designed for effortless pricing, buying, and selling pre-owned cars. This
mobile-first website is set to evolve into either a Progressive Web App (PWA) or a native
application. https://motorproz.co.uk/

## 2. Houmify.com, United States UI / UX Designer

01/2021 - 09/2023

 Designing the user experience also user interface and coordinating for a team dedicated to the redesign of a website focused on connecting users with real estate agents. https://houmify.com/

## 3. Houmify.com, United States UI / UX Designer

01/2021 - 09/2023

Key role in conceptualizing the user interface and experience for a website dedicated to
facilitating the buying and selling of gift items. I was responsible for creating a visually
engaging and intuitive design that seamlessly guided users through the process of selecting
and exchanging goods intended for gifting purposes. <a href="https://giftpals.com/">https://giftpals.com/</a>

## 4. Rayan Kavesh Hirkan, Iran UI / UX Designer

02/2020 - 01/2021

- A dual role of UI/UX Designer and Project Manager for an application catering to municipal
  waste collection and recycling. This encompassed the design of two distinct Android mobile
  apps—one tailored for staff and the other for users. This project involved several elements to
  ensure a seamless user experience while concurrently overseeing the work of front-end
  developers.
- A comprehensive software solution aimed at delivering medical equipment and services to homes via two mobile apps (the user version and the staff version). My role involved ensuring an optimal user experience through thoughtful design while also Leading the various aspects of the project to guarantee its successful execution.

### 5. Post Bank of Iran, Iran UX Consultant

10/2009 - 01/2020

- Head of bank representative offices for 8 years
- The UX consultant for the last two years to improve the bank counter processes and also ideation and design of communication software bridging cellphones and personal computers, ensuring a secure data transfer experience. My focus included crafting an intuitive interface for effortless interaction.

# 6. Farniroo Sharq company, Iran Graphic designer

03/2004 - 02/2009

Macromedia Flash Senior Designer and Computer technical expert (Part-time)

#### **Additional Experience**

Teaching graphic applications as a web-pages-design tool at Tehran Institute of Technology

#### Education

- Associate's Degree in Computer Science (Software Engineering)
   Khayyam University Mashhad Iran
- Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (Hardware Engineering)
   University of Shomal Amol Iran

#### Language

- English | Conversational
- Persian | Native

### Professional Training (Certificates)

#### 1. Faculty of Entrepreneurship, University of Tehran

- User Experience Design (UX)
- User Interface Design (UI)
- Financial Intelligence

#### 2. Google (online courses on Coursera.com)

- Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design
- UX Design process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate!
- · Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Prototypes

#### 3. Interaction Design Foundation (IDF)

- Design for the 21st Century with Don Norman
- Accessibility: How to Design for All
- Gamification Creating Addictive User Experiences
- Human-Computer Interaction (HCI)
- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- UX Management: Strategy and Tactics
- User Research Methods and Best Practices
- Psychology of E-commerce
- Mobile User Experience Design
- Web Design for Usability

#### 4. Imperial College London

• User Creative Thinking: Techniques for Success

#### 5. Iran Technical & Vocational Training Organization

- Adobe Photoshop CS
- Adobe Illustrators CC
- · General pedagogical methods

#### **Article and Success**

- <u>Utilization of new technologies to improve the UX and Accessibility</u>
- Second place in the U.S. Endourological Society Logo Design Contest